DENIS NEBESNOV

+7-921-000-00-61 • Alanya Turkey • Open to relocation

daaaesnov@gmail.com & Linkedin & Telegram

SUMMARY

With over a decade of experience in IT Project Development, Service Operations, and Project Management, I have consistently demonstrated my ability to lead and deliver successful outcomes. I've led diverse teams ranging from 5 to 40 members, effectively optimizing resource allocation for project success. My collaborative approach extends across all organizational levels, from frontline workers to senior executives. I've managed budgets ranging from

\$50k to \$2mln, ensuring efficient resource utilization. My expertise lies in adeptly navigating complex environments, addressing policy challenges, and overcoming bureaucratic obstacles while consistently achieving project objectives.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ITSM independent consultant | Part time Project manager, Freelance

Jul 2022 - Current

- Assisted with redesign process workflows, roles and responsibilities, documentation, and associated tools to reduce silos between teams and increase efficiency and decrease average time to resolution from 24 hours to 8 working hours.
- Consulted with ITSM tool selection by identifying key aspects for compare and business requirements, policies and current team experience. Researched 8 products and arranged 4 demonstrations with vendors or its partners.

Service Manager, Gazpromneft

Apr 2021 - Jul 2022

- Provided a cloud-based service CaaS (Containers as a Service) to approximately 120 internal development teams by managing service team of 8 engineers (3 FTE of 2nd line engineers, 3 FTE of development and maintain engineers + 2 FTE of 1st line support specialists).
- Developed and presented a new service, payment, and ordering process, negotiated over 100 projects and secured and signed contracts with over 80% of them.
- Streamlined end-to-end workflow and adjusted Jira for Support and Development teams. As a result, Increased number of incidents and requests resolved within SLA from 80% to 92%.
- Conducted collaborative meetings, enhancing planning efficiency and reducing consultancy requests from 20% to less than 5%. This effort also eliminated service incidents due to communication issues and speeded up service request assignments from 5 to 2 hours using a clear matrix and definitions.
- Optimized monitoring processes and implemented Grafana dashboards, resulting in a remarkable 83% reduction in monthly report preparation time from 24 hours to just 4 hours. This enhanced issue investigations, provided strong evidence during discussions, and effectively identified and addressed performance bottlenecks, leading to significant time and resource savings.
- Contributed to the launch of new services (CaaS, DaaS, PaaS) and established a comprehensive service catalog for the transition team. This involved developing architecture, budgets, service request catalogs, defining objectives, tariffs, developing SLAs, and contracts.

- Established and supervised technical support services, leading a team of 8 to 12 engineers covering both 1st and 2nd lines of support. Maintained over 5000 CI and delivered support to approximately 2500 users.
- Enhanced the Service Desk tool by implementing streamlined workflows tailored to request types, optimizing alerts, generating reports, and updating the service portfolio. This transitioned 30% of requests from phone or email to 80% through the customer portal, freeing up more time for maintenance and service requests.
- By initiating and managing the development of a PC inventory tool for 5000+ assets and introducing an annual technical audit for precise infrastructure insight, cost forecasting, and risk management, I improved asset-accounting alignment, simplified inventory processes, and saved 10-15% in CAPEX on user devices.
- In partnership with Ricoh, I enhanced the printing service by implementing a secure printing management system, Streamline NX, and unifying devices. This resulted in significant cost savings, with expenditures dropping from 1.2 million rubles per year for toner and spare parts to 800 thousand rubles. Additionally, we reduced incident requests by over 80%.

Project Manager, Kirov-Enorgomash

Apr 2010 - Jun 2012

- Managed a complex Nuclear Power Plant device development project, overseeing all stages from design to
 commissioning. With a budget exceeding 200 million rubles, over 5000 parts, a height requirement of 120
 meters, and a load capacity of 80+ tons, I ensured successful project completion while meeting deadlines,
 ensuring quality, and coordinating with contractors
- Analyzed cost projections, identified gaps in expenses and project duration estimates, and successfully
 negotiated contract changes, adding 30 million rubles to the contract cost and extending the due date by
 three years. Additionally, optimized control operations, saving over 20 million rubles and cutting production
 time by three months.

SKILLS

Tools and methodology: ITSM, Jira, Manage Engine, HPSM, BPMN, Waterfall, Kanban, Scrum, Power BI· MS Project, MS Excel, Grafana

Skills: Leadership, Project Management, Communication, Emotional intelligence, Coaching and Mentoring, Strategic Planning, Operation management, HR Management, Compliance and Regulations, Quality Control, Inventory Management, Risk Management

Language skills: Russian: native, English: Proficient (C1)

EDUCATION

Peter the Great St. Petersburg Polytechnic University BS: Information Technology in Industry

2010